A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Developing Countries Program, Vice President, Office Files of William D. Carmichael FA711
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Subjects, 1968-1989; V
  - Overseas Compensation, 1968-1979 (Box 8 (30280), Folder 21-23)
  - Overseas Compensation, 1980-1981 (Box 9 (30282), Folder 1)
  - Overseas Compensation – tax aspects, 1977-1980 (Box 9 (30282), Folder 2-3)
  - Population Council, 1976-1979 (Box 9 (30282), Folder 4-6)
  - Program planning functions, 1985-1987 (Box 9 (30282), Folder 7)
  - Program Related Investments – Hicks, Dan, 1986-1987 (Box 9 (30282), Folder 8)
  - Program Review, 1985-1989 (Box 9 (30282), Folder 9-15)
  - Program Support – proposed budget, 1988-1989 (Box 9 (30282), Folder 16-17)
  - Public Management in Developing Countries, 1972-1974 (Box 9 (30282), Folder 18-20)
  - Research Competition in International Security and Arms Control, 1979-1981 (Box 9 (30282), Folder 21)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Staff in India, 1988 (Box 9 (30282), Folder 22)
  - Rural Poverty and Resources Program Staff Meeting in Cairo, 1983 (Box 10 (47940), Folder 1)
  - Snow, Phillip, 1983 (Box 10 (47940), Folder 2)
  - Staff luncheons, 1976-1981 (Box 10 (47940), Folder 3)
  - Sutton, Francis X., 1981-1986 (Box 10 (47940), Folder 4)
  - Women's Program, 1977-1985 (Box 10 (47940), Folder 5-11)
- Board of Trustees, 1978-1989; VI
  Correspondence, memoranda, agendas, reports, briefing books and travel information, relating primarily to overseas meetings coordinated by William Carmichael and his staff. Included in some files are Carmichael's handwritten notes on meeting proceedings, and outlines for several of his presentations to the Board. Also a few files of correspondence with, and travel reports by, individual board members. Meeting minutes, dockets, reports and committee files previously and separately collected by the Archives are not included here. Access restricted to Ford Foundation staff.
  All contents of Series VI are restricted from scholarly access.
  - Dahrendorf, Ralf, 1981-1983 (Box 10 (47940), Folder 12)
  - Ellis, James, 1982 (Box 10 (47940), Folder 13)
  - McNamara, Robert S., 1983 (Box 10 (47940), Folder 14)
  - Marshall, Dorothy, 1981-1983 (Box 10 (47940), Folder 15)
  - Meetings, 1981-1987 (Box 10 (47940), Folder 16-34)
  - Meetings, 1987-1988 (Box 11 (47941), Folder 1-5)
  - Meetings in Africa - Briefing materials, 1982 (Box 11 (47941), Folder 6-7)
  - Meetings in Africa - Correspondence, 1982 (Box 11 (47941), Folder 8-9)
  - Meetings in Africa - Nairobi program, 1982 (Box 11 (47941), Folder 10)
  - Meetings in Africa - Schedules, 1982 (Box 11 (47941), Folder 11-12)
  - Meetings in Latin America - Briefing book, 1986 (Box 11 (47941), Folder 13)
  - Meetings in Latin America - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 11 (47941), Folder 14)
  - Meetings in Latin America - Country briefings, 1986 (Box 11 (47941), Folder 15-18)
  - Meetings in Latin America - Country briefings, 1986 (Box 12 (47942), Folder 1-2)
  - Meetings in Latin America - Security, 1986 (Box 12 (47942), Folder 3)
  - Meetings in Latin America - Travel briefings, 1986 (Box 12 (47942), Folder 4)
  - Meetings in Latin America - Travel schedules, 1986 (Box 12 (47942), Folder 5)
  - Meetings in New Delhi – itinerary, 1978 (Box 12 (47942), Folder 6)
  - Meetings in Southeast Asia - Background readings, 1989 (Box 12 (47942), Folder 7-10)
  - Meetings in Southeast Asia - Itineraries, 1989 (Box 12 (47942), Folder 11-12)
  - Meetings in Southeast Asia - Planning, 1989 (Box 12 (47942), Folder 13)
  - Meetings in Southeast Asia - Schedules, travel and accommodations, 1989 (Box 12 (47942), Folder 14-16)
  - Milliken, William, 1983 (Box 12 (47942), Folder 17)
  - Preiskel, Robert, 1983 (Box 12 (47942), Folder 18)
  - Rabb, Harriet S., 1981-1983 (Box 12 (47942), Folder 19)
  - Spencer, Edson W., 1981 (Box 12 (47942), Folder 20)
- Appendix A: Reports
  - Anderson, Bernard E. Urban poverty program assessment (Report 11096)
  - Bailey, Charles R. Farmer Participation in Improved Irrigation Management, 1987 (Report 16694)
  - Bailey, Charles R. Ford Foundation rural employment program in Bangladesh: future directions, [1987?] (Report 11733)
  - Bailey, Charles R. [Programming guidelines], 1987 (Report 12561)
  - Bailey, Charles R. Water, land, and people in the Sudan and Egypt, 1985 September (Report 3924)
  - Barber, Elinor G. Visit to Nairobi, 1980 March (Report 16723)
  - Barsalou, Judith Marie. The war in Lebanon: overview of the costs of the war, relief efforts, and the Foundation's past involvement in the country, 1982 September 15 (Report 11709)
  - Bell, David E. The International Agricultural Research Centers and the Ford Foundation, 1981 October (Report 9493)
  - Bok, Derek Curtis and Sutton, Francis X. Possible courses for development of the Aga Khan University, 1983 October (Report 11717)
  - Bonbright, David W. Significant features of the South African context, [Fall, 1987?] (Report 11768)
  - Booker, Salih. Program strategy paper: Governance and Public Policy, 1987 January 9 (Report 11718)
  - Bratton, Michael. The politics of government-N.G.O. relations in Africa, 1987 December (Report 11704)
  - Bratton, Michael. Program strategy statement: governance for rural development, 1986 September 23 (Report 11511)
  - Bresnan, John. International economic and political issues: the view from Southeast Asia, 1982 April 23 (Report 11732)
  - Bresnan, John and Curtis, Gerald L. Trilateral Commission meeting: Beijing: memorandum and 3 reports, 1981 October 15 (Report 11686)
  - Brunner, Jose Joaquin. La educacion superior en America Latina: los problemas de la universidad y una propuesta de trabajo, 1988 (Report 11916)
  - Carmichael, William D. Mexico and the United States: new opportunities for the Ford Foundation, 1981 May 28 (Report 11724)
  - Carmichael, William D., Chen, Lincoln C., Winder, David. Recent developments in Nicaragua, Nigeria and Assam and possible Foundation responses: memorandum and 3 reports, 1983 March (Report 11688)
  - Cavarozzi, Marcelo. Governance and public policy program for the Philippines, 1986 December (Report 11008)
  - Chambers, Robert J. H. Appraising and improving canal irrigation, 1981 April (Report 11807)
  - Chambers, Robert J. H. People and common property resources in land: concept and issues paper: Staff Meeting, Rural Poverty and Resources Program (Report 11140)
  - Chang, Martha. The Ford Foundation and China, 1987 August 10 (Report 16995)
  - Chen, Lincoln C. Social development in India and the role of international agencies: presentation to the Indian Administration Service Academy, Mussoorie, India, 1985 November (Report 11908)
  - Chen, Lincoln C. Culture strategy paper, [ca. 1982] (Report 11810)
  - Chen, Lincoln C. Interaction of health technology and social organization: the Takemi lecture, Harvard School of Public Health, 1984 March 18 (Report 11762)
  - Chen, Lincoln C. The role of a private philanthropy in India, 1984 September 9 (Report 11763)
  - Chen, Lincoln C. and Measham, Anthony R. Health, 1979 June 13 (Report 16704)
  - Clark, Lance. Early warning issues regarding the current influx into Somalia, 1986 April 25 (Report 11721)
  - Cleaves, Peter S. Field offices and management options for the International Division (Report 10042)
  - Cleaves, Peter S. Summary of January 1979 Consultancy Reports on U.S.-Mexican Relations, 1979 March 15 (Report 16697)
  - [Consultants Group on The AIDS challenge: a Ford Foundation response, 1987 AIDS Policy] (Report 11277)
  - [Cool, John]. Bangkok meeting on culture and the arts, Wednesday, June 4, 1980: rapporteur's notes on the afternoon session (Report 7157)
  - Del Castillo, Romulo A. Upland development program: a progress report, 1982 November 17 (Report 11737)
  - Edwards, Robert H. Southern Africa: program directions (Report 7409)
  - Ellsworth, Lynn. Rural institutional development in West Africa: some grant-making principles, 1988 June (Report 11921)
  - Enabling Environment Conference (1986 Oct. 21-24). Effective private sector contribution to development in Sub-Saharan Africa: conference papers (Report 12073)
  - Feinberg, Richard E. Ford Foundation support for international economics programs in the Andean and Southern Cone regions of Latin America, 1986 (Report 11682)
  - Fitch, John Samuel. Development of the governance program for the Andean and Southern Cone region of the Ford Foundation, 1987 (Report 11690)
  - Ford Foundation. Background Information on Indonesia, Philippines and Thailand, 1986 (Report 16711)
  - Ford Foundation. Background papers: symposium on expanding income earning opportunities for women in poverty: a cross regional dialogue sponsored by the Ford Foundation, Women's Program Forum, Nairobi, Kenya, 1988 May 1 - 5 (Report 15493)
  - Ford Foundation. Briefing Notes on the Thailand Upland Social Forestry Project, 1989 March (Report 16712)
  - Ford Foundation. Child Survival/Population Meeting, 1986: Kathmandu, Nepal. Proceedings and background papers (Report 11708)
  - Ford Foundation. Developing Country Programs FY1983 program reviews: Rapporteur notes / [by] Ford Foundation, Developing Countries (Report 8321)
  - Ford Foundation Developing Country Programs: FY 1986 program reviews, 1985 September 30 - October 5 (Report 11488)
  - Ford Foundation Developing Country Programs: FY 1988 program reviews, 1987 October 21 - 30 (Report 11663)
  - Ford Foundation. Discussion Notes. The Ford Foundation in the Caribbean (Report 16709)
  - Ford Foundation. Ford Foundation, India, Nepal, Sri Lanka: annual report, October 1981 - September 1982 (Report 11950)
  - Ford Foundation. Meeting on Ford Foundation Community Level Action program: Ford Foundation, New York City: transcript, 1980 July 24 (Report 1027)
  - Ford Foundation. New Delhi office program statement: fiscal years 1981-82, 1980 October (Report 11951)
  - Ford Foundation. Program statements: Southeast Asia Regional Office, 1983 Mar. Ford Foundation, Field Office, Jakarta, 1983 March (Report 11753)
  - Ford Foundation. Report on a Ford Foundation rural economy team's visit to China, 1980 (Report 5870)
  - Ford Foundation. A report to the Southeast Asia regional office of the Ford Foundation on possible funding opportunities in the field of human rights and social justice in Thailand, 1987 May (Report 12306)
  - Ford Foundation. Rural poverty and agriculture: a report on the Ford Foundation's work in agroecosystems and farming systems research, 1987 January (Report 11120)
  - Ford Foundation. Rural Poverty and Resources Programming in Thailand, 1986 (Report 16713)
  - Ford Foundation. Staff Seminar on Public Management in Peru, 1973 November 13 (Report 16710)
  - Ford Foundation. Staff workshop on human rights: January 18-22, 1987, London, England (Report 11674)
  - Ford Foundation. World meeting on Education and Culture: May 13-17, 1985, Bali, Indonesia (Report 11666)
  - Forman, Shepard. Staff workshop on human rights: March 10-13, 1985, Ica, Peru (Report 11667)
  - Foster, Don and Sandler, Diane. A study of detention and torture in South Africa: preliminary report, 1985 September (Report 11770)
  - Fry, Peter. Grant making in Mozambique: report on June 17-July 3 visit to Maputo and Nampula, 1989 July (Report 11913)
  - Fry, Peter. The social sciences in Mozambique: a long-term strategy, 1989 April (Report 11912)
  - Gadalla, Saad. The Shanawan Experimental Rural Development Project Interim Report 1975-1979, 1980 January (Report 16693)
  - Gerhart, John Deuel. Agricultural productivity, concepts and issues paper: prepared for Staff Meeting, Rural Poverty and Resources Program, 1983 (Report 11139)
  - Germain, Adrienne. Reflections on women's health programming in the Delhi office, 1986 March (Report 11914)
  - Goldmann, Robert B. Report on the Trincomalee, Sri Lanka, Workshop on Preference Policies, 1982 March 30 (Report 16703)
  - Goldmann, Robert M. Report on Israel VI, 1981 September (Report 12769)
  - Gupta, Ranjit, and Sharan, Girja. Appraisal of ICA's approach, activities and accomplishments, 1983 April 26 (Report 12482)
  - Harkavy, Oscar. Ford Foundation Population Council Collaboration Overseas, 1976 June 28 (Report 16692)
  - Harkavy, Oscar. International Conference on Population, Mexico City, August 6-14, 1984, 1984 September 21 (Report 16720)
  - Hicks, Frank. The potential for program-related investments in the Ford Foundation's developing country programs, 1987 April 20 (Report 11909)
  - Hooker, Michael. Moral values in private philanthropic activity: a background paper for a conference on private philanthropy and the social good, 1985 October 29 - 30 (Report 11676)
  - Horovitz, Richard A. Senegal, Mali and Ivory Coast Portions of Jim Ellis' West Africa Trip, 1982 March 19 (Report 16714)
  - Horovitz, Richard A. Trip Report – Gaborone, Botswana, December 6-11, 1979, 1979 December 19 (Report 16718)
  - Horovitz, Richard A. Trip Report: Guinea, April 1-3, 1985, 1985 April 19 (Report 16715)
  - Howard, Craig. Program statement for urban community development, 1984 October 8 (Report 11693)
  - Humphreys, John and Kessinger, Tom G. Preliminary report on recent developments in the Philippines, 1986 March 15 (Report 11751)
  - Hyden, Goran. Approaching rural development through village-level projects: criteria for undertaking pilot, experimental or demonstration projects, 1980 (Report 11714)
  - Hyden, Goran. Ethiopia – Changes at the Horizon?, 1983 (Report 16731)
  - Hyden, Goran. Fostering progress in Africa: the need to think the present crisis historically, 1984 (Report 11716)
  - Hyden, Goran. A grave new world?, 1983 November 28 (Report 11702)
  - Hyden, Goran. The population scene in Kenya, 1983 May (Report 11523)
  - Hyden, Goran. Proposal to establish a sub-office in Zimbabwe, 1982 (Report 11694)
  - Hyden, Goran. Rural community development: role of community-based and intermediary organization: concepts and issues paper: Staff Meeting, Rural Poverty and Resourses Program (Report 11141)
  - Hyden, Goran. The Situation in Nairobi, 1984 December 7 (Report 16724)
  - Hyden, Goran. State of Affairs in Kenya, 1982 August 30 (Report 16721)
  - Hyden, Goran. Ten years of Foundation support for the social sciences in Eastern and Southern Africa: evaluation of DAPs 759-0807 and 829-0784, 1984 September 4 (Report 11695)
  - Hyden, Goran. Visit to Somalia, 1982 June 18 (Report 16719)
  - Hyden, Goran. Zimbabwe Update, 1983 March 21 (Report 16725)
  - Jones, David. Rural social sciences and policy: concepts and issues paper: Staff Meeting, Rural Poverty and Resources Program (Report 11143)
  - Joseph, Richard A. Human Rights, Governance and International Affairs in West Africa, 1988 March 15 (Report 16716)
  - Joshi, Deep and Narain, Ravi. The role of rural banking in poverty alleviation programs in India: background and program possibilities, 1984 December (Report 11817)
  - Kallapur, Sanjay. A sample survey of corporate philanthropy in India: (summer assignment with the Ford Foundation, New Delhi), 1984 (Report 11819)
  - Kerkvliet, Ben. Findings and recommendations regarding program possibilities for the Ford Foundation in Philippine public affairs (Report 8390)
  - Klausner, William. Reflections, 1985 February 12 (Report 11758)
  - Klausner, William. Reflections on the Thai body politic and Ford Foundation programming, 1989 January (Report 11755)
  - Kocher, James E. and Harkavy, Oscar. My comments and recommendations for FF health and nutrition programming, 1980 October 16 (Report 11814)
  - Korten, David C. Management of Social Transformation at National and Sub-National Levels, 1981 March 24 (Report 16726)
  - Korten, Frances F. A Participatory Approach to Irrigation Development: Experience from the Philippines, 1982 (Report 16722)
  - Krystall, Abigail. Population and development in Kenya: programme suggestions for the Ford Foundation, 1985 November (Report 11691)
  - Lenton, Roberto L. People and forests: a report of a Ford Foundation meeting on a social forestry and agro-forestry (Report 10400)
  - Lenton, Roberto L. Water management: concepts and issues paper: prepared for Staff Meeting, Rural Poverty and Resources Program, 1983 May (Report 11138)
  - Lesch, Ann Mosely. The Ford Foundation in Egypt, 1983 December 10 (Report 11711)
  - Lesch, Ann Mosely. The Middle East in International Politics, 1982 August 23 (Report 16717)
  - Lowenthal, Abraham. Consultant's report to the Ford Foundation Mexico office (Report 8950)
  - Lowenthal, Abraham. U.S.: Mexican relations, 1980 October 5 (Report 8951)
  - McLean, Sheila Avrin and Micou, Ann McKinstry. Trip report, 1987 September - October (Report 11766)
  - McLean, Sheila Avrin. Visit to South Africa, 1978 January 10 (Report 11769)
  - McKee, Katharine. Improving rural employment and incomes: concept and issues paper: Staff Meeting, Rural Poverty and Resources Program, 1983 May (Report 11142)
  - McKee, Katharine. Staff meeting on Livelihood, Employment and Income Generation: Dhaka, April 1984: summary, agenda, and notes (Report 11703)
  - Measham, Anthony R. and Simmons, Ozzie G. Health/Nutrition/Population (HNP) Explorations in Columbia, 1980 May 8 (Report 16700)
  - Measham, Anthony R. and Simmons, Ozzie G. Health/Nutrition/Population (HNP) Explorations in Mexico, 1980 May 5 (Report 16699)
  - Measham, Anthony R. and Simmons, Ozzie G. Health/Nutrition/Population (HNP) Explorations in Peru, 1980 May 12 (Report 16705)
  - Measham, Anthony R. and Teitelbaum, Michael S. Health/Nutrition/Population (HNP) Explorations in Nigeria, January 15-24, 1981, 1981 January 26 (Report 16702)
  - Mosley, W. Henry. Report on the trip to Egypt for Child Survival/Fair Start Program Mar. 31 - Apr. 16, 1982 (Report 11747)
  - Myers, Robert G. External Financing of Foreign Study: The Ford Foundation in Peru, 1983 (Report 16707)
  - Myntti, Cynthia. Program opportunities in North Yemen, 1983 March 7 (Report 11698)
  - Naik, Chitra. An action-research project on universal primary education: the plan and the process, ca.1982 (Report 11806)
  - Nasson, Bill. Politics and crisis: reflections on the state of the Western Cape 1981-1987, 1987 June (Report 11771)
  - Obasanjo, Olusegun and Deng, Francis Mading. The search for peace in the Sudan: the challenge of maintaining the peace process, 1987 (Report 11680)
  - Picken, Margo and Stover, Eric. An evaluation of the International Human Rights Internship Program, 1988 June (Report 11911)
  - Plant, Roger. Human rights and public affairs in the Philippines, 1984 August (Report 8162)
  - Poffenberger, Mark. Notes on land reform in the Philippines, 1988 February 11 (Report 11683)
  - Poffenberger, Mark. Why forestry in Southeast Asia?, 1986 May 16 (Report 11734)
  - Rajapurohit, A. R. Tasar silk programme for women: a techno-economic evaluation, 1985 Jan. / A. R. Rajapurohit. (Report 11994)
  - Rampal, N. N. Workshop on Corporate Philanthropy held at New Delhi on October 14-15 1985, 1985 Nov./sponsored by the Centre for Policy Research, New Delhi and the Ford Foundation, New Delhi, 1985 October 14 - 15 (Report 11910)
  - Remenya, Joseph V. Trade, Aid and Monopolistic Pricing, 1976 December 17 (Report 16698)
  - Rocheleau, Dianne E. Draft program strategy paper for Rural Poverty and Resources: addressing landscape domestication in marginal lands through tree-based innovations in policy, management and technology, 1986 November 10 (Report 11692)
  - Rocheleau, Dianne E. A summary of progress, lessons learned and new directions in the rural poverty and resources program strategy for Eastern and Southern Africa, 1989 (Report 11905)
  - Rubin, George. Nepal Child Survival meeting: Dhaka Field Office visit, 1986 April 5 - 25 (Report 11685)
  - Ruof, Peter. Foundation Program on Mexican-U.S. Relations, 1979 March 6 (Report 16696)
  - Sanderson, Steven E. CIEPLAN evaluation, 1988 July 18 (Report 11684)
  - Schulz, Michael. Report on a Visit to Cairo and Tanta, 1985 March 10 - 23 (Report 16727)
  - Seckler, David William. The new era of irrigation management in India, 1981 January (Report 11808)
  - Seckler, David William. Restoration of the Himalayas, 1980 September 24 (Report 11809)
  - Seeger, Anthony. Final report of the consultancy on the archive of traditional music at the Riva Aguero Institute, Pontifical Catholic University of Peru (PUCP) in Lima, 1987 March 25 (Report 11675)
  - Simmons, Ozzie G. Health/Nutrition/Population Activities in Thailand, 1980 April 1 (Report 16701)
  - Smith, Ted. Some Tentative Thoughts on a Broader Framework for Addressing the Relevance and Appropriateness of Technical Assistance Strategies Designed to Encourage Administrative Capacity in the Less Developed Countries, 1973 March 8 (Report 16706)
  - Snow, Philip C. H. Survey of the historical and modern relations between the Chinese and African peoples: final report to the Ford Foundation, 1983 (Report 12143)
  - Stearns, Katherine E. Meeting the needs and potential of informal firms through microenterprise promotion, 1985 June (Report 11761)
  - Sutton, Francis X. American philanthropy in educational and cultural exchanges with the People's Republic of China, 1985 January (Report 11007)
  - Sutton, Francis X. Poland, 1982 June 23 (Report 11662)
  - Thomas, Franklin A. Preliminary recommendations on the Foundation's future directions, 1981 March (Report 11504)
  - Unakul, Snoh Thailand: Economic Policy and Prospects, 1989 March 6 (Report 16708)
  - Vance, Amy S. Promoting and protecting women's rights and opportunities: suggested new directions for the Ford Foundation's Women's Rights program (Report 6843)
  - Venkataraman, K. and Chen, Lincoln C. The devil's lexicon on grant management: a squint eye view, 1985 January 31 (Report 11996)
  - Vindasius, Julia. Thoughts on Grameen Bank: working document: Grameen Bank-Good Faith Fund lessons, 1988 September 20 (Report 11739)
  - Wallach, Bret. The development of irrigation in the Sudan, 1988 (Report 11726)
  - Wallach, Bret. The development of rainfed agriculture in the northern Sudan, 1988 February (Report 11725)
  - Werley, Carolyn C. A survey of American private voluntary organization involvement in Sub-Saharan Africa, 1981 February (Report 11915)
  - Winder, David. Position paper on Ford Foundation's Nicaragua program, 1983 March 10 (Report 11701)
  - World Bank. Report of the External Advisory Panel on Education to the World Bank, 1978 October 31 (Report 16728)
  - World Bank. Report of the External Advisory Panel on Education to the World Bank [draft], 1978 August (Report 16729)